<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux4Chemistry (C)</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://linux4chemistry.github.io/categories/c.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 21:05:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Situs</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/situs.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Situs is an award-winning program package for the modeling of atomic resolution structures into low-resolution density maps e.g. from electron microscopy, tomography, or small angle X-ray scattering. The software supports both rigid-body and flexible docking using a variety of fitting strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C</category><category>Crystallography</category><category>Docking</category><category>GPL</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/situs.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SNF</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/snf.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;SNF has been developed for the calculation of Infrared, Raman, and VROA spectra using the harmonic approximation for the frequencies and the double harmonic approximation for the intensities. Vibrational frequencies are determined using numerical differentiation of analytical gradients of the total electronic energy, while infrared, Raman, and VROA intensities are obtained by numerical differentiation of dipole moments and (generalized) polarizability tensor components with respect to nuclear coordinates. Single point calculations are carried out using ADF, Dalton, Gaussian, Molpro or Turbomole.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>Fortran</category><category>GPL</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/snf.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GDIS</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gdis.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GDIS (GTK Display Interface for Structures) is a visualization program for small molecules, crystals, and solution cells. It has support for common crystallographic file formats, and assorted tools for visualization (including diffraction pattern generation), manipulation, and model creation. Rendering of molecules and energy minimization are also possible via Povray and GULP.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C</category><category>Crystallography</category><category>GPL</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gdis.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GPeriodic</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gperiodic.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GPeriodic is a periodic table application for Linux. It allows you to browse through a periodic table of the elements and view detailed information on each of the elements on each of the elements. 118 elements are currently listed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><category>Periodic Table</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gperiodic.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>PyMOL</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/pymol.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;PyMOL is a molecular graphics system with an embedded Python interpreter designed for real-time visualization and rapid generation of high-quality molecular graphics images and animations. It can also perform many other valuable tasks (such as editing PDB files) to assist you in your research.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C</category><category>Lua</category><category>Python</category><category>Python License</category><category>Tcl</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/pymol.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>XmMol</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/xmmol.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;XmMol is a desktop macromolecular visualization and modeling tool designed to be easy to use, configure and enhance. Its graphics are based on X11, and part of its user interface is based on Motif. Thus it provides a way of displaying structures on any X11 server.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/xmmol.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>XPovChem</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/xpovchem.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;XPovChem is a molecule viewer based on the PovRay raytracer. It takes a molecule description, converts it into a .pov file, and lets povray render the image -- thus allowing a very high rendering quality. Xpovchem includes the professional Babel molecule format converter and is a GUI frontend to Paul Thiessen's povchem console program.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/xpovchem.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>AMMP</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ammp.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;AMMP is a modern full-featured molecular mechanics, dynamics and modeling program. It can manipulate both small molecules and macromolecules including proteins, nucleic acids and other polymers. In addition to standard features, like numerically stable molecular dynamics, fast multipole method for including all atoms in the calculation of long range potentials and robust structural optimizers, it has a flexible choice of potentials and a simple yet powerful ability to manipulate molecules and analyze individual energy terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><category>Molecular Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ammp.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MEXICO</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mexico.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;MEXICO simulates the NMR lineshapes of coupled spin systems undergoing chemical exchange. It will simulate systems and, if experimental data are available, it will perform an iterative fit to give optimized values of the parameters.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><category>NMR</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mexico.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>RasMol</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/rasmol.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;RasMol is a molecular graphics program intended for the visualisation of proteins, nucleic acids and small molecules. The program is aimed at display, teaching and generation of publication quality images.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/rasmol.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>