<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux4Chemistry (Posts about Docking)</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://linux4chemistry.github.io/categories/docking.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 21:27:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>AutoDock</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/autodock.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;AutoDock is a suite of automated docking tools. It is designed to predict how small molecules, such as substrates or drug candidates, bind to a receptor of known 3D structure. Search methods include evolutionary methods such as the Lamarckian Genetic Algorithm, in addition to the Monte Carlo simulated annealing (SA) method.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C++</category><category>Docking</category><category>GPL</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/autodock.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chimera</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/chimera.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Chimera is an extensible molecular modeling system that can be used for molecular visualisation, addition of hydrogens, volumetric data, displaying the results of MD simulations, viewing the output of DOCK, and it has support for writing extensions in the Python scripting language.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>Docking</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/chimera.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dockres</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/dockres.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Dockres reads the log file of docking runs performed by Autodock and extracts the top scoring poses subject to various filters. The program also calculates distributions of various properties of the ligand set (e.g. molecular weight, number of hydrogen bond donors) and the distribution of docking sites as well as the distribution of docking free energies per target residue.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/dockres.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>eHiTS</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ehits.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;eHiTS (Electronic High Throughput Screening) is a program for flexible docking of ligands to proteins. It is fast, fully automated, and comprehensively covers the searc space.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ehits.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FlexV</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/flexv.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;FlexV is a general-purpose molecular viewer. It is a stand-alone tool with easy interfaces, and can be used in combination with any kind of molecular modeling software, although originally designed as a visualisation front-end for FlexX.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/flexv.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GOLD</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gold.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GOLD is a program for calculating the docking modes of small molecules into protein binding sites as part of a virtual screening application. Docking is performed using a genetic algorithm and incorporates full ligand flexibility and partial protein flexibility. The GoldScore and ChemScore scoring functions are available, or a custom scoring function can be implemented. Cavity-bound waters and constraints can be included as part of the docking procedure.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gold.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GRAMM</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gramm.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GRAMM (Global Range Molecular Matching) is a program for protein-protein and protein-ligand docking. To predict the structure of a complex, it requires only the atomic coordinates of the two molecules. The program performs an exhaustive 6-dimensional search through the relative translations and rotations of the molecules.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gramm.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GRID</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/grid.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GRID is a computational procedure for determining energetically favourable binding sites on molecules of known structure. It may be used to study individual molecules such as drugs, molecular arrays such as membranes or crystals, and macromolecules such as proteins, nucleic acids, glycoproteins or polysaccharides.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Cheminformatics</category><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/grid.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MGLTools</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mgltools.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;MGLTools is a suite of software including PMV (Python Molecular Viewer), a molecule viewing and manipulation environment, ADT (AutoDockTools) for looking at AutoDock results, and pyBabel, a Python re-implementation of some of the features of Babel v1.6.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>Cheminformatics</category><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mgltools.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Molegro Virtual Docker</title><link>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/molegro-virtual-docker.html</link><dc:creator>l4c</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Molegro Virtual Docker is an integrated platform for predicting protein-ligand interactions. It handles all aspects of the docking process from preparation of the molecules to determination of the potential binding sites of the target protein, and prediction of the binding modes of the ligands.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Docking</category><guid>https://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/molegro-virtual-docker.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>