<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux4Chemistry (Molecular Dynamics)</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://linux4chemistry.github.io/categories/molecular-dynamics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 21:05:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>ORAC</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/orac.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;ORAC is a molecular dynamics program for running classical simulations of solvated biomolecules. Simulations can be carried out in the NVE, NPT, NHP, and NVT thermodynamic ensembles using multiple time steps integrators. Electrostatic interactions may be handled through the Smooth Particle Mesh Ewald method.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Fortran</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/orac.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WHAT IF</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/what-if.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;WHAT IF is a versatile protein structure analysis program that can be used for mutant prediction, structure verification, molecular graphics, displaying the results of GROMACS calculations, analyse electron density maps, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>Crystallography</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/what-if.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>AMMP</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ammp.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;AMMP is a modern full-featured molecular mechanics, dynamics and modeling program. It can manipulate both small molecules and macromolecules including proteins, nucleic acids and other polymers. In addition to standard features, like numerically stable molecular dynamics, fast multipole method for including all atoms in the calculation of long range potentials and robust structural optimizers, it has a flexible choice of potentials and a simple yet powerful ability to manipulate molecules and analyze individual energy terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><category>Molecular Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ammp.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MDTools</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mdtools.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;MDTools is a collection of programs, scripts, and utilities to make various molecular dynamics tasks easier, and to provide basic code and utilities which can be built up into larger toolsets.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mdtools.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>CP2K</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/cp2k.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;CP2K can perform atomistic and molecular simulations of solid state, liquid, molecular and biological systems. It provides a general framework for different methods such as e.g. Density functional theory (DFT) using a mixed Gaussian and plane waves approach (GPW), and classical pair and many-body potentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Fortran</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/cp2k.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EGO</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ego.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;EGO is a parallel program for molecular dynamics simulations of biomolecules. The program computes molecular dynamics trajectories. It uses a multiple time step algorithm combined with a structure adapted fast multipole method for the description of long range electrostatics. The method has been demonstrated to scale linearly with the number of atoms in the range of about 40,000 atoms.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ego.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MCCCS Towhee</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mcccs-towhee.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;MCCCS Towhee is a Monte Carlo molecular simulation code which can be used for the prediction of fluid phase equilibria using a wide variety of atom-based force fields and several ensembles (Gibbs, Canonical, Isobaric-isothermal and Grand Canonical). It has also been extended for use with solid (or porous) phases.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>Fortran</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/mcccs-towhee.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Packmol</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/packmol.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Packmol creates an initial point for molecular dynamics simulations by packing molecules in defined regions of space. The packing guarantees that short range repulsive interactions do not disrupt the simulations. The great variety of types of spatial constraints that can be attributed to the molecules, or atoms within the molecules, makes it easy to create ordered systems, such as lamellar, spherical or tubular lipid layers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/packmol.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>XMD</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/xmd.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;XMD performs Computer Molecular Dynamics (CMD) simulations on metals and ceramics.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/xmd.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BallView</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ballview.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;BallView is a cross-platform molecular visualization tool with support for molecular mechanics optimisation, molecular dynamics and molecular editing. It supports a large number of file formats, SMILES and SMARTS, as well as forcefields such as Amber, MMFF94 and Charmm. Its capabilities also include realtime raytracing and stereoscopic viewing. Actions can be automated using Python scripts.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C++</category><category>GPL</category><category>Molecular Dynamics</category><category>Molecular Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/ballview.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>