<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux4Chemistry (Quantum Mechanics)</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://linux4chemistry.github.io/categories/quantum-mechanics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 21:05:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>GTK-Gamess</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gtk-gamess.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GTK-Gamess is a frontend to GAMESS that allows users to queue up GAMESS calculations and run them sequentially.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>C++</category><category>GPL</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gtk-gamess.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SNF</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/snf.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;SNF has been developed for the calculation of Infrared, Raman, and VROA spectra using the harmonic approximation for the frequencies and the double harmonic approximation for the intensities. Vibrational frequencies are determined using numerical differentiation of analytical gradients of the total electronic energy, while infrared, Raman, and VROA intensities are obtained by numerical differentiation of dipole moments and (generalized) polarizability tensor components with respect to nuclear coordinates. Single point calculations are carried out using ADF, Dalton, Gaussian, Molpro or Turbomole.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>C</category><category>Fortran</category><category>GPL</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/snf.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaguar</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/jaguar.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Jaguar is an ab initio electronic structure software package that provides chemical accuracy for realistic systems, with particular strength in treating metal-containing systems. Calculations are efficient and scale well with molecular size.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/jaguar.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ABINIT</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/abinit.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;ABINIT is a package whose main program allows one to find the total energy, charge density and electronic structure of systems made of electrons and nuclei (molecules and periodic solids) within Density Functional Theory (DFT), using pseudopotentials and a planewave basis. Excited states can be computed within the Time-Dependent Density Functional Theory (for molecules), or within Many-Body Perturbation Theory (the GW approximation).&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Fortran</category><category>GPL</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/abinit.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WIEN2k</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/wien2k.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;WIEN2k allows the user to perform electronic structure calculations of solids using density functional theory (DFT). It is based on the full-potential (linearized) augmented plane-wave ((L)APW) + local orbitals (lo) method, one of the most accurate schemes for band structure calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/wien2k.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Khimera</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/khimera.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Khimera is a software tool for the estimation of thermodynamic properties and kinetic rate parameters based on results of quantum-chemical calculations (supports GAMESS, Gaussian, Jaguar, ADF). Reactor models included in KHIMERA help to create and test the mechanism of chemical processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><category>Reactions</category><category>Thermodynamics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/khimera.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GaussSum</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gausssum.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;GaussSum is a GUI application that can analyse the output of Gaussian 98/03, ADF, GAMESS (US), GAMESS (UK), and PC-GAMESS calculations to extract and calculate useful information. This includes the progress of the SCF cycles, geometry optimisation, UV-Vis/IR/Raman spectra, MO levels, MO contributions and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>GPL</category><category>Python</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><category>Utility</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/gausssum.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ADF</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/adf.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;ADF is the Amsterdam Density Functional program system for high-quality computational chemistry research. The two main programs are ADF, for molecules, and BAND for periodic structures: polymers, slabs, and crystals. Several smaller utility and property programs are available for pre- and post-processing data of the main calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/adf.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>DL Visualize</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/dl-visualize.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;DL Visualise provides a powerful interface for constructing and visualizing crystals, surfaces and molecules and their properties. It has interfaces to CRYSTAL, DX_EXCURV and GULP.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>Crystallography</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/dl-visualize.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MOLEKEL</title><link>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/molekel.html</link><dc:creator>linux4chemistry</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;MOLEKEL is an interactive, three-dimensional molecular graphics package. MOLEKEL represents molecules,it can superimpose molecules, calculates and displays isosurfaces of electron and spin densities as well as molecular orbitals from the output of various electronic structure calculation programs. MOLEKEL can animate and display vibrational modes, animate geometry optimizations and multiple coordinate PDB and XYZ files.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>3D Viewer</category><category>Quantum Mechanics</category><guid>http://linux4chemistry.github.io/posts/molekel.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>